consciouslifenews.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy : Conscious Life News

## Who we are

We are Conscious Life News. Please see our Mission Statement [**HERE**](https://consciouslifenews.com/mission/). Our website address is: https://consciouslifenews.com. To contact us, please use our contact form [**HERE**](https://consciouslifenews.com/contact-us/).

## What personal data we collect and why

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Your email address is optional. Do not enter your email address if you don't want it collected or displayed.

If you do enter your email address, an anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. (The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>.) After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should **avoid** uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

As mentioned above, you can contact us via our contact form [**HERE**](https://consciouslifenews.com/contact-us/). Your name and email address are required so that we can respond to your request. When you submit your name, email, and message, it results in an email being sent to: admin@consciouslifenews.com and is flagged as coming from the Contact Us form. Your details are not stored anywhere other than in the email that is generated.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Analytics

We are not currently collecting any analytic data.

## Who we share your data with

We do NOT share your data with anyone.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

For users who subscribe to our newsletter, your name and email address are stored in our email program until you unsubscribe (which you can do by clicking an UNSUBSCRIBE link at the bottom of any email you receive from us).

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.  Make your requests via our contact form [**HERE**](https://consciouslifenews.com/contact-us/).

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Contact information

Should you have any privacy-specific concerns, please contact us via our contact form [**HERE**](https://consciouslifenews.com/contact-us/).
